Finding Aid for Jane Lockwood Barney papers
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Jane Lockwood Barney Papers
1937-2009
1980-2005
Barney, Jane Lockwood.
2013044 Aa 2
Ann Arbor, Michigan, Social Worker, Jane Lockwood Barney, worked for decades in organizations related to aiding the elderly, minorities, homeless, and hungry. Her primary organizations were: Avalon Housing, Inc., Shelter Association of Washtenaw County, St. Andrew's Episcopal Church, Washtenaw Housing Alliance, Turner African American Services Council, and the New Hope / University of Michigan Geriatric Clinic (now called the New Hope Outreach Clinic). The collection encompasses material related to Jane Barney's activities after the passing of her husband, Roger Warren Barney, in 1978. The series in the collection are organized by Professional Files and Personal Files. Papers include primarily meeting minutes, professional and personal correspondence, reports, and administrative notes, awards and recognitions, photographs, and family materials.
12 linear feet
1 oversize folders
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donated by Jane Barney (Donor no. 10050 ) in March and December of 2012.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Jane Lockwood Barney was a social and political activist who worked to establish, build, and run a number of organizations aimed to improve the lives of the people of the Ann Arbor area. Her causes included access to high quality health care for minorities and the elderly, homelessness, hunger, job skills training, and Democratic political activism. She attended Wellesley College, Union Theological Seminary, and the University of Michigan School of Social Work.
Jane Lockwood Barney was married to Reverend Roger Warren Barney, and they had three sons and a daughter; Alice B., James O., Jonathan L., and Daniel R. From 1948 to 1967 the family lived at Parishfield, a community devoted to "renewal of the church" where Reverend Barney was one of the three clergy in charge of community management at Parishfield.
Jane Barney was a founder of the Michigan Association of Nursing Home Community Councils, co-founder and President of the Avalon Housing Board, co-Chair of the Turner African American Services Council, and Chair of the Turner Geriatric Clinic Advisory Committee. She served on the Community Development Executive Committee and the boards of the Washtenaw Housing Alliance, Community Council Association, the Housing Bureau for Seniors, and the Shelter Association of Washtenaw County/Ann Arbor. From 1970 to 1989 she worked at the University of Michigan's Institute of Gerontology. After her retirement from the Institute of Gerontology in 1989, she remained active in many organizations and in the Ann Arbor community.
The Jane L. Barney papers are comprised of materials documenting her professional and personal life. The Professional Files include organization meeting minutes, correspondence, notes, flyers, manuals, press articles, and personnel files, as well as other administrative papers and reports for the organizations she worked to establish, develop, and run. Also found here are speeches, papers relevant to her work with churches, minorities, and gerontology.
Jane L. Barney's personal papers largely include correspondence with friends, co-workers, politicians, and family, as well as notebooks, diplomas, hospital and assisted living documentation, and photographs.
Subjects:
Barney, Jane Lockwood.; Avalon Housing (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Institute of Gerontology (University of Michigan-Wayne State University); Shelter Association of Washtenaw County.; St. Andrew's Episcopal Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Turner African American Services Council.; Washtenaw Housing Alliance.; African Americans--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Housing--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Minorities--Michigan--Washtenaw County.; Nonprofit organizations--Michigan--Washtenaw County.; Older people--Michigan--Washtenaw County.; Women in nonprofit organizations--Michigan--Washtenaw County.
Genre Terms:
Audiocassettes.; Photographs.; Slides (photography)
- Professional Files
  The Professional Files series is divided into nine subseries: Biographical, Avalon Housing, Inc., Shelter Association of Washtenaw County, St. Andrew's Episcopal Church, Washtenaw Housing Alliance, Turner African American Services Council, New Hope / University of Michigan Geriatric Clinic (now called the New Hope Outreach Clinic), Projects and Involvement, and Written Works. The series focuses on her involvement and day to day running of the organizations and encompasses her activities from her time as a student to her position at the University of Michigan's Institute of Gerontology.
  Papers include organization meeting minutes, correspondence, notes, flyers, manuals, press articles, and personnel files, as well as other administrative papers and reports for the organizations she worked to establish, develop, and run. The Written Works subseries contains papers and articles written by or about Jane Barney. Also found here are speeches, papers relevant to her work with churches, minorities, and gerontology.
  - Biographical, 1976-2002
    - Biographical, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Curriculum Vitae and Career Objective, 1976-2002 (scattered) (Box 1)
      (includes a summary of Barney's life before gerontology)
    - Letters of Reference, 1984-2002 (Box 1)
    - Life before Gerontology, 1990-1999 (Box 1)
    - Resumes, 1950-1980s (Box 1)
    - Retirement from the Institute of Gerontology, 1985-1989 (Box 1)
      (mostly correspondence)
  - Avalon Housing, Inc.
    - 1990 (Box 1)
    - 1991 (Box 1)
    - 1992 (Box 1)
    - 1993, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - 1994 (Box 1)
    - 1995-1998 (Box 1)
    - 1999-2000 (Box 1)
    - Annual Reports, 1994; 2001-2004 (Box 1)
    - Avalon Services Issue, 1998 (Box 1)
    - Board Membership, 1992-2003 (scattered) (Box 1)
    - Board of Trustees and Directors
      - 1992-1993 (Box 1)
      - 1994 (Box 1)
      - 1995 (Box 1)
      - 1996-1997 (Box 1)
      - 1998 (Box 1)
      - 1999 (Box 1)
      - 2000-2001 (Box 1)
      - 2001-2002 (Box 1)
      - 2002-2004 (Box 1)
      - 2005-2007 (Box 1)
    - By-Laws, 1995 (Box 2)
    - Community Development Block Grants, 1993-1995 (Box 2)
    - Dhu Varren Housing Project, 2001-2003 (Box 2)
    - Financial Statements with Auditors' Reports (Box 2)
      - 1994-1995 (Box 2)
        (Federal Awards Supplemental Information and Consolidated Financial Report)
      - 1996-1999 (Box 2)
      - 2000-2001 (Box 2)
    - Fundraising
      - 10th Anniversary Benefit, 2002 (Box 2)
      - Affordable Housing Fund Committee, 1998-2000 (Box 2)
        (joint campaign with the Locals Initiatives Support Corporation (LISC))
      - Committee Meetings (Box 2)
        - 1993-1998 (scattered) (Box 2)
        - 1998 (Box 2)
        - 2000-2003 (Box 2)
          (mostly 2000)
      - Home Is Where the Art Is: A Mosaic Campaign for Carrot Way, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Housing Policy Board, 1994-1996 (Box 2)
    - Ingalls House, 1990-1993 (Box 2)
    - Jane's Donation, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Organizational Retreat, 1999-2001 (Box 2)
      (includes reports from 1995 and 1997 retreats)
    - Origin, 1993-1995 (Box 2)
    - Personnel Committee, 1994-2000 (Box 2)
    - "Pilot Light" -- Avalon Tennant Organization Newsletter, 1996; 1999-2003 (Box 2)
    - President and Executive Director Roles, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Promotional Materials, 1994-2002; 2009 (scattered) (Box 2)
    - Property Management Records, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Staff Compensation Committee, 1998-1999 (Box 2)
    - YMCA Residential Program, 1996; 2000 (Box 2)
  - Shelter Association of Washtenaw County
    - 60-Day Policy, 1996-1997 (Box 2)
    - Ann Arbor Homeless Survey, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Board of Directors
      - 1988 (Box 2)
      - 1989-1990 (scattered) (Box 2)
      - 1990, 2 folders (Box 2)
      - 1992-1993 (Box 2)
      - 1992-1994 (scattered) (Box 2)
      - 1993 (Box 3)
      - 1993-1994 (Box 3)
      - 1994 (Box 3)
      - 1994-1995 (Box 3)
      - Executive Director (Paula Stewart) Work Plan, 1994-1995 (Box 3)
    - By-Laws, 1987-1994 (Box 3)
    - Donor List, 1996 (Box 3)
    - Downtown Shelter, 2001; 2003-2004 (Box 3)
    - Downtown Sheltering Neighbors Advisory Committee, 1999-2000 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous Documents, 1996-2005 (scattered) (Box 3)
    - Personnel, 1990-1994 (Box 3)
    - Problems, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
      (Maintenance, property inspections)
    - Programs, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
    - Shelter Art Project, 2001 (Box 3)
    - Shelter and Clinic, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
    - Shelter Publications, 1993 (Box 3)
    - Task Force on Homelessness
      - Ad Hoc Housing, 1992-1994 (Box 3)
      - Ad Hoc Night Shelter Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 3)
      - Final Report, 1997 (Box 3)
      - Joint Steering Committee, 1998-1999 (Box 3)
      - Mission Clarity Group (MCG) Final Report, 1997 (Box 3)
      - Phase II, 1997 (Box 3)
      - Subcommittee Meetings and Reports, 1997 (Box 3)
    - Warming Center, 1996-1998; 2000 (Box 3)
  - St. Andrew's Episcopal Church
    - Canterbury House
      - Bylaws of the Episcopal Student Foundation, 1994 (Box 3)
      - Lawrence, (Reverend) Matthew, 1996-2003 (scattered) (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous, 2000-2001 (scattered) (Box 3)
    - Church Vision, 2001-2002 (Box 3)
    - Economic Justice Task Force, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Eileen Schulmeister Community Reception, 1998 (Box 3)
    - Episcopal Student Foundation Board Retreat, 1997 (Box 3)
    - Job Intern Program (JIP)
      - 1992-1996 (Box 3)
      - Family Self Sufficiency Program, 1994 (Box 3)
      - Hero Mentor, 1996 (Box 3)
      - Interns, 1992-1996 (Box 4)
      - Mentor Training, 1995 (Box 4)
      - Mentoring Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 4)
      - Planning, 1992-1996 (Box 4)
      - Program Plan, 1990-1996 (Box 4)
      - Reports on Interns, 1992 (Box 4)
      - Vestry Report, 1997-1998 (Box 4)
      - Work First, undated (Box 4)
    - Outreach Profile, 1998-1999 (Box 4)
    - Outreach and Social Justice Committee
      (later renamed to Outreach Committee)
      - 2001-2003 (Box 4)
      - 2001, 2003-2004 (Box 4)
    - Religious Action for Affordable Housing (RAAH), 2000-2005 (Box 4)
  - Washtenaw Housing Alliance (WHA)
    - Affordable Housing Task Force Committee
      - 1999-2000 (Box 4)
      - 2000 (Box 4)
      - 2003 (Box 4)
        (Supportive Housing)
    - Annual Report, 2007 (Box 4)
    - Board Meetings and Correspondence
      - 2000
        - Articles of Incorporation, Bylaws, and Role and Key Functions of the Board of Directors (Box 4)
        - General (Box 4)
        - WHA Business Plan for the Operation of the Huron Street Shelter, Final Draft, March 2000 (Box 4)
      - 2001 (Box 4)
      - 2002, 2 folders (Box 4)
      - 2003 (Box 4)
      - 2004 (Box 4)
    - Community Shelter Board, 2001-2002 (Box 4)
    - Downtown Development Authority (DDA) -- Housing and Parking, 1997-2004 (scattered) (Box 4)
    - Ellsworth Proposal, 1998 (Box 4)
    - Housing Policy Board, 1997-1998 (Box 4)
    - Interfaith Hospitality Network of Washtenaw County (IHNWC), 1996-2000 (scattered) (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1994-2006 (Box 4)
    - Statement of Purpose and Articles of Incorporation, 2000; 2002 (Box 4)
  - Turner African American Services Council (TAASC)
    - Action Committee Meeting Minutes, 1989-1990 (Box 5)
    - Advisory Council
      - 1977-1981 (Box 5)
      - 1982-1987 (Box 5)
      - 1984-1989 (Box 5)
      - 1984-1994 (Box 5)
      - Membership, 1982-1989 (Box 5)
      - Structure, 1988 (Box 5)
    - By-Laws, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Campbell, Ruth, 1984 (Box 5)
      (Social Worker/Social Gerontologist)
    - Coliver Pharmacy Presentation, 1996 (Box 5)
    - Committee Recommendations, 1994-1995 (Box 5)
    - Community Coalition, 1992 (Box 5)
    - Community Health Education Resource Center (CHERC), 2001 (Box 5)
    - Cultural Sensitivity Training Committee, 1994-1998 (Box 5)
    - Delaney Sisters Performance, 1997 (Box 5)
    - Development Position Paper, circa 1970s (Box 5)
    - Diversity and Healthcare Poster, 1999 (Box 5)
      (includes photos)
    - Environment and Client Care Committee, 1994 (Box 5)
    - Foster African American Health Study, 1994 (Box 5)
    - Funding, circa 1988 (Box 5)
    - General Meetings and Correspondence
      - 1984-1986 (Box 5)
      - 1985-2000 (Box 5)
      - 1995-1999, mostly 1997-1998 (Box 5)
      - 1999-2001 (Box 5)
      - 2003-2009 (Box 5)
      - Bluhm, Rick, 1998-2000 (Box 5)
      - Campbell, Ruth, 1994-2004 (Box 5)
      - Colligan, Kristin, 1998-1999 (Box 5)
      - Key Letters, 1994-2003 (Box 5)
      - Redmer, Sharon, 2000 (Box 5)
    - Guidelines for Serving African American Patients, 1997-1998 (Box 5)
    - Hartford Foundation
      - Consortium, 2000-2004 (Box 5)
      - Fellowships, 2002-2003 (Box 5)
    - Health Guide Distribution Committee
      - Appeals, 1998 (Box 5)
      - Final Report, December 1999 (Box 5)
      - HOPE, 1999 (Box 5)
      - Minutes, 1998-1999 (Box 5)
      - Printing, 1999 (Box 6)
      - Project, 1998-2001 (Box 6)
    - Hengstebeck Interview Project, 1998 (Box 6)
    - History, 1976-1998 (Box 6)
    - Institute of Gerontology Involvement, 1974-1977 (Box 6)
    - J. Barney Appointments, 1974-1988 (Box 6)
    - Kelley, William, 1984 (Box 6)
      (UM Professor and Chairman of Department of Internal Medicine)
    - Kirkpatrick, Dorothy, 1992-2001 (scattered) (Box 6)
      (Educational Specialist)
    - Library, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 6)
    - Membership, 1994-1995 (Box 6)
    - Membership Committee, 1994-1999 (Box 6)
    - Minority Medical Student Reception, 1996-1999 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous
      - 1995-2000 (Box 6)
      - African American Healthcare History, 1996-1999 (Box 6)
    - Newsletters, 1987-1989 (Box 6)
    - Outreach Committee
      - 1994-1995 (Box 6)
      - Pittenger Letter, 1987 (Box 6)
    - Peer Counselors, 1988 (Box 6)
    - Penchansky Study, 1979 (Box 6)
    - Personal Notes
      - 1993-1998 (Box 6)
      - 1999 (Box 6)
    - Poster, 1994 (Box 6)
    - Program Development Committee, 1996 (Box 6)
    - Programs
      - 1980-1989 (Box 6)
      - 1990-1997 (Box 6)
    - Recruitment Committee, 1993-1998 (Box 6)
    - Reports, 1994 (Box 6)
    - Retreats, 1993 (Box 6)
    - Steering Committee
      - Minorities Access Subcommittee
        - General, 1990-1991 (Box 6)
        - Minority Access Pilot Project, 1990-1992 (scattered) (Box 6)
      - 1990-2000 (scattered) (Box 6)
        (includes papers from when TAASC was the Minority Access Subcommittee)
      - 1995-1997 (Box 7)
      - 1998-2001 (Box 7)
        (mostly 1999-2000)
      - 2000-2002 (Box 7)
        (includes a photo and negatives of Dr. Bass, and a computer printed photo of JLB w/ someone at the clinic)
      - Meeting Minutes
        - 1993-1994 (Box 7)
        - 1995-1997 (Box 7)
    - Turner Geriatric Clinic
      - 1977-1989 (Box 7)
      - 1978-1981 (Box 7)
      - Concept Paper, 1976 (Box 7)
      - Development, 1977 (Box 7)
      - Planning, 1976 (Box 7)
    - Turner Senior Resource Center
      - General, 2005 (Box 7)
      - Silver Club, 2000 (Box 7)
    - Turner Space Program, 1996 (Box 7)
    - University of Michigan Health Services (UMHS) Community Outreach, 1998 (Box 7)
    - University of Michigan Hospitals Minority Healthcare Initiative, 1993 (Box 7)
    - Washtenaw County Task Force on African American Health
      - 1996-1998 (Box 7)
      - Community Health Committee, 1996-1999 (Box 7)
      - Umoja, 1997-1998 (Box 7)
        (Celebration of African American Manhood)
  - New Hope / University of Michigan Geriatric Clinic (Box 7)
    - Action Plan, 2001-2002 (Box 7)
    - Adult Day Care, 1999-2003 (Box 7)
    - Advisory Board
      - 1998-2002 (Box 7)
      - 2003-2005 (Box 7)
    - Development, 1991-1995 (Box 7)
    - Dr. Lightfoot, 1995-2002 (scattered) (Box 7)
    - Fundraising, 2000-2001; 2005 (Box 7)
    - Geriatric Clinic, 1992-2005 (Box 7)
    - Gordon Meeting, 2001 (Box 8)
    - Grants
      - Ann Arbor Area Community Foundation, 1995 (Box 8)
      - Faith In Action, 2001 (Box 8)
      - Innovations in Health Professions Education, 1997 (Box 8)
    - Groundbreaking, 2000 (Box 8)
    - Health Connexion, 2001-2003 (Box 8)
    - Job Descriptions, 1982-2000 (Box 8)
    - Learning in Retirement, 1990-1995 (Box 8)
    - Lease, 2000 (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous Administrative, 2001 (Box 8)
    - Mobile Unit, 1996 (Box 8)
      (Construction Plans for Outreach Clinic)
    - Neighborhood Meetings and Correspondence, 1998 (Box 8)
    - New Building Correspondence and Background, 1996 (Box 8)
    - New Hope Baptist Church, 1996-2007 (Box 8)
    - Northcross, Winnie, 2000-2002 (Box 8)
      (City Clerk)
    - Notes, 1996-1997 (Box 8)
    - Pilot Project Proposal, 1993 (Box 8)
    - Planning Sub-committee, 2000 (Box 8)
    - Preliminary Plan, 1995 (Box 8)
    - Press, 1998-1999 (Box 8)
    - Project Meeting, 1997-1998 (Box 8)
    - Proposal for a University of Michigan Geriatrics Center/New Hope Baptist Church Outreach Clinic, 1994; 1997 (Box 8)
    - Staff Meetings, 2001-2005 (Box 8)
    - Statistics, 1990-1996 (Box 8)
    - Steering Committee, 1995-2000 (scattered) (Box 8)
    - Zoning Board, 1997-1998 (Box 8)
  - Projects and Involvement
    - Ann Arbor
      - Allen Creek, 1999 (Box 8)
      - City Appointments, 1991-1998 (Box 8)
      - Community Development Department, 1996 (Box 8)
      - Income Tax Levy, 1991 (Box 8)
      - Parking Survey, 1989 (Box 8)
    - Church
      - Black Churches Initiative, 1993-1994 (Box 8)
      - Seabury Caucus, 1973 (Box 8)
        (a discussion of the role of the church in human affairs)
    - Gerontology
      - Alcohol Metabolism and Aging Research Study, 1992 (Box 8)
      - Alzheimer's, 1996 (Box 8)
      - Area Agency on Aging 1-B, 1999 (Box 8)
      - Committee on Alternative Adult Living Arrangements, 1996-1997 (Box 8)
      - Michigan Society of Gerontology, 1988 (Box 8)
      - National Citizens' Coalition for Nursing Home Reform, 2000-2001 (Box 8)
      - Neighborhood Senior Services, 1996-2001 (Box 8)
      - Nursing Home Presentation and Regulations, 1992-2001 (Box 8)
      - Robinson Alzheimer's Project, 1998 (Box 8)
    - Housing
      - Ann Arbor City Council Affordable Housing, 1999 (Box 8)
      - Ann Arbor City Planning, 1987-2000 (Box 8)
      - Ann Arbor Housing Commission, 1995-1997 (Box 8)
      - Ann Arbor Inn, 1993 (Box 8)
      - Cots Shelter, 1995 (Box 9)
      - Fair Housing Center for Washtenaw, 1994-2001 (Box 9)
      - Homeless Action Committee, 1989-1992 (Box 9)
      - Michigan Housing Trust, 1994-2000 (Box 9)
      - Michigan State Housing Coalition, 1995-1998 (Box 9)
      - Rent Stabilizing Coordinating Committee, 1988 (Box 9)
      - Vivienne Housing, 1998 (Box 9)
      - Washtenaw Affordable Non-Profit Housing Corp., 1987-1994 (Box 9)
    - Hunger
      - Ann Arbor Hunger Coalition, 1995-1996 (Box 9)
      - Food Gatherers, 2000 (Box 9)
    - Minority
      - African American Health Summit, 1997 (Box 9)
      - Diversity and Career Development Committee (DCDC) Community Relations Task Force, 1997-1998 (Box 9)
      - Diversity Fund, 1997 (Box 9)
      - Diversity and Healthcare Conference, 1999 (Box 9)
      - Minority Health Coalition, 1995-1998 (Box 9)
      - NAACP, 1994 (Box 9)
      - Trailblazers, 1990-2000 (Box 9)
        (Mental Illness Support)
    - Miscellaneous, 1993-2001 (Box 9)
    - Nursing Homes Community Councils
      - Community Councils Association, 1989-1992 (Box 9)
      - Organizers Manual, Fall 1980 (Box 9)
      - Personal Thanks to Community Councils Association (CCA), 1986 (Box 9)
      - Project
        - 1978-1980 (Box 9)
        - 1980-1984 (Box 9)
      - Publicity, 1980-1990 (Box 9)
      - Six-Case Study, 1980 (Box 9)
    - University of Michigan Institute of Gerontology
      - Correspondence, 1982-1988 (Box 9)
      - Elderly Support System Program, 1982 (Box 9)
      - Improving the Environment for Living in Long-term Care Institutions Project, 1977 (Box 9)
      - Nursing Aid Training Program, 1989 (Box 9)
      - Nursing Home Advocacy: Issues Presentation, 1980 (Box 9)
        (two cassette tapes and one box of projector slides)
      - Nursing Home Patient Survey, 1973 (Box 9)
    - Washtenaw County
      - Continuum of Care for Washtenaw County, 1987 (Box 10)
      - Dispute Resolution Center, 1998 (Box 10)
      - Prison CURE Program, 1997-2001 (Box 10)
  - Written Works
    - Aging, 1977-1987 (Box 10)
    - The Ferndale Wall and The Study of Ferndale, Michigan, 1968 (Box 10)
    - Institute of Gerontology Papers, 1970-1987 (Box 10)
    - Michigan Nursing Home Staff Development Project, Summer 1981 (Box 10)
      (Contains all material from Nursing Aid Training Program)
    - Papers at Union, 1937-1940 (Box 10)
      (Includes 2 folders of religious papers written by Jane Barney during her time at Union Theological Seminary)
    - Papers at University of Michigan, 1965-1970 (Box 10)
    - The Pauline Conception of Deliverance from Sin, May 1940 (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous Papers and Reports, 1944-2001 (scattered) (Box 10)
    - Presentations, 1982 (Box 10)
    - Various Speeches, 1975-1990 (Box 10)
    - Bound Materials
      - "Common Concern: A New Perspective on Nurse's Aide Training," Geriatric Nursing: American Journal of Care for the Aging, Vol. 4, No. 1, January / February 1983 (Box 10)
      - "Community Presence as a Key to Quality of Life in Nursing Homes," American Journal of Public Health, Vol.64 No. 3, Pp. 203-300, March 1974 (Box 10)
      - "Nursing Directors in Nursing Homes," Nursing Outlook, Vol. 22 No. 7, July 1974 (Box 10)
      - Patients in Michigan's Nursing Homes: Who are they? How are they? Why are they there?, November 1973 (Box 10)
      - "That Ol' Time Religion Is Really Gone," You'd Better Listen, Mr. Charlie, an Urban Training Center pamphlet series, No. 2, September 1968 (Box 10)
      - The New Hampshire Churchman: Diocese of New Hampshire
        - Vol. 7 No. 8, "Four Books for Christmas,", November 1954 (Box 10)
        - Vol. 8 No. 5, "Bunyan Revisited,", May 1955 (Box 10)
      - The Well-Being Report: A Look at Supportive Services for the Elderly, 1975 (Box 10)
    - Reports on Gerontology and Nursing Homes (to which Barney contributed), 1974-1984 (Box 10)
- Personal Files
  The Personal Files series is divided into eight subseries: Correspondence, Family, Education, Political Affiliations, Assisted Living, Awards and Recognitions, Photographs, and Miscellaneous. Jane L. Barney's personal papers largely include correspondence with friends, co-workers, politicians, and family. This series also comprises documents from her time as a student at Wellesley College, Union Theological Seminary, and University of Michigan School of Social Work. Notebooks, diplomas, hospital and assisted living documentation, and photographs also are located in this series.
  - 80th Birthday Weekend Event, 1994 (Box 11)
  - Daily Planners, 1970-1971; 1975-2000 (Box 11)
  - FBI Files, 1991 (Box 11)
    (2 folders for Roger and Jane Barney regarding an investigation on the Kercheval Street Riot in the late 1960s)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970 (Box 11)
  - Parishfield, 1957-2003 (scattered) (Box 11)
    (includes correspondence, a small collection of Shells by J. B. Guinan, a Parishfield brochure, and an autobiographical account of Barney's time at the Parishfield Community)
  - Snowville: The Barney Epoch, Summer 1991 (Box 11)
  - Wellesley Scholarship Donation, 2002 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence
    - 68 South State Street: Letters from Jane L. Barney 1955-1956, 1987 (Box 11)
      (a bound book of letters written by Jane Barney)
    - Ann Arbor News Editor, 1990-2002 (Box 11)
    - Ayres, 1967-2008 (scattered) (Box 11)
    - Ayres, Mimi, 2003-2005 (scattered) (Box 11)
    - Celebration of Women Selections Committee, 1998-2000 (Box 11)